Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well. Today, we're going to
talk about a boring topic, which is
boredom. Let's talk about being bored.
This is not something that people like.
For many people, this is a terrible
feeling. Especially for kids. I remember
when I was a kid, when I felt bored, it
was awful. I complained.
I whined.
Right? Where you complain in that voice
that kids make when they're not happy.
Uh I would tell my parents that I was
bored, that I wasn't happy.
People don't like being bored, of
course.
Uh a lot of people hate this feeling.
And uh I think that nowadays,
kids don't really have many
opportunities
to be bored like when I was a kid.
Because nowadays, kids have so many
different things, different forms of
entertainment.
Uh
they have phones and screens,
and they can always watch something if
they feel bored. I didn't have that when
I was a kid.
Sometimes, I was just in my room, bored,
with nothing to do. And I can remember
that feeling very well. Today, I think
that
uh kids always have something to do.
They can always find something to
entertain them. Right? So, it's a little
different nowadays. Uh
as an adult, when you're an adult, you
don't really have as much time to be
bored. Right? We have many things to do.
Many responsibilities.
Uh there are always things that I need
to do,
uh places I need to go, people I need to
help. Uh if you have a family, if you
have kids, of course,
uh you spend time with them, you help
them, you do things for them. So, as an
adult,
you don't really have as much time to be
bored. And honestly, being bored is not
always a bad thing.
Okay? I know we don't like being bored,
but boredom is actually an important
thing.
For example, it's important to have some
time where
you're not doing anything, and you don't
have stimulation.
Things that are making your brain and
your eyes work.
Sometimes, it's important to just do
nothing. This is like rest for your
brain. It's important for your brain to
rest, and not always be doing something.
Right? So, boredom can be important for
that reason.
You don't want to always be bored, but
sometimes, being bored and doing nothing
can give you and give your brain the
rest that it needs. Right? Uh being
bored can also be a good thing because
it gives us time to think and to
organize our thoughts, and to
come up with ideas, to think of new
ideas.
Sometimes,
when you
uh just turn everything off, all the uh
screens and entertainment, and you just
uh stay alone with your thoughts uh in
some room or outside or something, you
think differently. You can think more
clearly,
and have different thoughts.
Uh sometimes, you might think of things
when you're bored that you didn't think
of when you were watching something, for
example. So, boredom can be good to help
you think better, think differently.
Uh it also can motivate you to be
productive. Uh
if you are bored for a long time, maybe
you
uh want to start working and doing
something that is productive. It
motivates you to be productive. Right?
That's another good thing. And also,
boredom teaches you to be patient. This
is especially good for kids. Uh
kids need to learn to
uh sit down for a while, and not have a
game or a screen or something. Uh my
kids, for example, are learning to sit
down the whole time when we're at
church, for example. So, uh my son is
getting better at sitting on his seat
for the whole time uh that we're there.
And at the beginning, it wasn't easy
because he got bored, he wanted to do
things and go places, but that boredom
and sitting there, it was like training.
He trained to be able to be patient and
sit down in the same seat for 1 hour. Uh
that is a skill that we need. Kids need
to develop patience. So, if they uh have
some boring parts of their day, it
teaches them to just be patient and wait
for the next thing. So, that is a good
thing as well. So, even though I don't
have a lot of time to be bored,
I still get bored of certain things. Uh
sometimes, I get bored of certain
languages that I'm learning. And then, I
stop, and I learn a different language.
And then, maybe in the future, I return
to that first language, and then it's
fun again. Sometimes, if something is
boring for us, we can just switch, we
can change to something else, and then
come back to it. So,
uh boredom can come, and you can
uh use it to also try new things. It
motivates you to try new things, and
then go back to the old things. Maybe
you're getting bored of English right
now. Maybe you just need to try
something different with your English.
Maybe if you have been watching movies
in English, and you're bored of that,
maybe you can start listening to music
in English, or listening to podcasts in
English. Uh if you change to a different
activity, then you might not be bored
anymore. So, just a piece of advice.
Boredom is a normal part of everyday
life. Uh boredom is a normal thing we
experience. It can be hard. It can be
frustrating. But,
boredom can be a good thing, and it can
help us
in some ways. And if you're feeling
bored, if you have something that is
boring for you now, maybe you can
change things a little.
And then in the future, you can come
back to that thing, and it won't be
boring. So, I just talked for like 10
minutes about boredom, about being
bored. This is a boring topic, but I try
to talk about everything, so you get
experience listening to me talking about
different topics. Hopefully, the next
topic will be a funner one than this
one, but I know that this was good
practice for your listening. If you want
harder content, more advanced content,
click on the link below to sign up for
my advanced podcast episodes, in which I
speak fast. Okay?
Thank you all for watching this video,
and I'll talk to you in the next one.